<?xml version="1.0"?>
<data>
	<metadata>
		<page_title_element>Frequently Asked Questions</page_title_element>
		<meta_title>.</meta_title>
		<meta_keywords>.</meta_keywords>
		<meta_description>.</meta_description>
	</metadata>

	<heading>Common Questions on Assisted Living</heading>
		<question>Can they take care of my loved ones needs?</question>
		<answer>There are so many different types of care available to seniors today. It is important to take a step back and evaluate the support  each  of these health care providers offer.  This can be as simple as visiting the health care provider for the afternoon and getting a  feel from the interaction of caregivers and residents, talking with current residents, asking for references as well as past inspections reports by governing bodies.</answer>
	
		<question>Is this location convenient for my loved one, myself, and other supportive family members?</question>
		<answer>Finding a good health care provider is hard. Finding assistance  that  is conveniently located to primary family members, social support groups , doctor's offices, hospitals, and familiar activities can be challenging. Remember location, location, location.</answer>
	
		<question>Can we afford this?</question>
		<answer>Detail is so very important here.  Take time and figure out if you or your loved one can afford this in the short term as well as the long term.  Your loved one may be here for quite a while and their health care needs may  change.</answer>
	
		<question>What are the terms of care?</question>
		<answer>Make sure you understand what services each health care provider will be responsible for.  Remember, your loved ones'  health care needs can change dramatically.  Please understand that some health care providers may only provide  up to a certain level of care and after that you have the responsibility to seek higher levels of care.</answer>
	
		<question>Is this a place I could see myself in?</question>
		<answer>We often project our own needs in situations that don't warrant it, however in cases like these, your needs are just as important as your loved ones.  Knowing your loved one is in a place that you  yourself would live in will save you many sleepless nights.  Knowing that you can have a meal with them at the same place will save you many bellyaches.</answer>

	<heading>Housing Definitions</heading>
		<question>What is Assisted Living?</question>
		<answer>The term assisted living relates to health care providers  that assists with activities of daily living.  These activities include but are not limited to, assistance with showers, medication administration, meal  preparation, housekeeping , companionship, and general assistance with daily tasks and errands. Assisted Living comes  in a variety of care packages such as independent living, assisted living communities, group homes, residential care homes, adult foster homes, nursing facilities, Alzheimer's  care units, memory care, and hospice units.</answer>
	
		<question>What are Residential  Care Homes?</question>
		<answer>Residential Care Homes provide assistance with activities of daily living in a smaller home-like environment.  These homes are often called Residential Care Homes, Personal Care Homes, Group Homes, Adult Care Homes, Board and Care Homes, and Adult Foster Care Homes.
		This is a wonderful choice for the individual that does not want to be in a large facility.  This care option is often the preferred choice for families and individuals that are cost conscientious  but still want a similar level of care offered by larger Assisted Living Facilities and Nursing Homes</answer>
	
		<question>What are Memory Care units?</question>
		<answer>Memory Care Units are specialized Assisted Living providers that care for  individuals that have been diagnosed with  Alzheimer's, dementia, or an impairment of cognitive function.  These providers can fall under the range of traditional Nursing Homes, Assisted Living Facilities, and specialized Residential Care Homes.</answer>
	
		<question>What are Home Care Providers?</question>
		<answer>Home Care Providers assist with activities of daily living in the comfort of your loved ones home.  These activities include but are not limited to, assistance with showers, medication administration, meal  preparation, housekeeping , companionship, and general assistance with daily tasks and errands.  Home Care Providers can be registered nurses, certified nursing assistance, certified caregivers, and caring individuals that have worked with similar health concerns as you loved one.</answer>
</data>
